

# **Mahmudul Hassan**

■ mahmudul.hassan240@gmail.com

**\** 01630811624

GitHub

**in** LinkedIn

▶ Portfolio

### **Career Objective**

Conscientious and diligent individual with **2.5+ years of experience** looking for a position where I could leverage my existing skills to enhance the quality of the target application along with improving my learning curve which would contribute to my personal career growth that indeed helps in the position.

#### **Skills**

Languages

Python, Javascript

**Frontend Framework & Libraries** 

Reactis, Jquery

**Database** 

MySQL, Postgres, Redis

**Programming Knowledge** 

Object-Oriented Programming,Problem Solving,Data Structure & Algorithms

**AWS** 

Lambda Server, Cognito, SAM(AWS Serverless Application Model), Api Gateway.

**Web Frameworks** 

Django, Django Rest Framework, FastAPI

**Design Technologies** 

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

**Operating System** 

Linux(Ubuntu), Windows

**Deployment & Others** 

Nginx, Gunicorn, Docker, RabbitMQ

### **Professional Experience**

12/2022 – present **Software Engineer,** *Gold Kinen Technology* ☑

My core responsibilities are designing and developing the backend along with front-end development. Mainly I have to work with Python, Django, FastAPI,

AWS Lambda Server, React, and more technologies.

10/2021 − 11/2022 **Software Engineer,** *Arbree Solutions* ☑

Dhaka, Bangladesh My core responsibilities are designing and developing backend along with

frontend development.

06/2021 – 09/2021 **Software Engineer,** *Heavy Task LLC* ☑

Dhaka, Bangladesh I am responsible for defining, developing, and evolving software in a fast-paced

and agile development environment using the latest software development

methods and infrastructure.

05/2020 - 05/2021	<b>Software Engineer,</b> Software Global Consultancy ♂
Dhaka, Bangladesh	I had been a Back-end Developer(Python) at SGC. I was responsible for
	developing and designing API endpoints, custom functionality development,
	and bug fixing. Moreover, I played a mediocre frontend and DevOps role when
	required.

#### **Education**

06/2015 – 06/2019 Dhaka, Bangladesh	<b>BSC in Computer Science &amp; Engineering,</b> <i>Daffodil International University</i> I have completed my graduation with a CGPA of 3.98 out of 4.
05/2012 – 05/2014 Dhaka, Bangladesh	<b>HSC,</b> <i>BAF Shaheen Collage Dhaka</i> I have completed my Higher Secondary Certificate with GPA of 5.00 out of 5.00 from the science group.
Dhaka, Bangladesh	SSC, Banani Bidyanikatan School & Collage I have completed my Secondary School Certificate with GPA 5.00 out of 5.00 from science group.

### **Some Of My Office Projects**

### Gold Kinen App.

Gold Kinen is Bangladesh's first hallmarked & certified 22 Karat Gold buy, sell & storage app. I am responsible for creating different services using techniques like FastAPI, AWS Lambda Server, React, Nodejs, ExpressJs, and more.

### Instant Job-hub LMS 🗷

Instant Job-hub Ltd is a renowned market leader focusing on Defense admission coaching. Recently they have started their EdTech journey through launching online courses and exams. I was played the role of a Teamlead for this project. I crafted the scalable architecture and design pattern of this project. We implemented some complex and unique features on this LMS. I lead a team of 5 people and ensured the successful delivery of this project.

### GProjukti.com 🛮

GProjukti Limited is an IT Accessories and Servicing Web application backed-up with Central Inventory and Store Management System. I was responsible for core backend development alongside frontend.

### Online Travel Agency(Air & Hotel)

This is on going micro service architecture based application. I am responsible for creating different service using different technology like FastAPI, NestJs, MongoDB, RabbitMQ, Redis, Celery.

### **Immigration Software for Lawyers**

Working on an immigration software and case management for immigration lawyers. In this project i am responsible for designing backend.

#### FIELDPROS CRM

Custom CRM Development for the home services industry.

### **Bangladesh Cadet College Admission System**

I was a team player in this large scale project. I integrated the payment gateway for this project and brought some feature changes as per requirements.

### **BGB Employee Management**

I contributed in backend(django) for this existing project. Worked on report generation and fixed some issues

### **Fire Service Training**

I contributed to the backend(django) for this existing project. Add some new features as per requirements and fix some issues

#### IPort 2.0

IPort 2.0 is a dynamic form generation system for Tekmark Group's internal requisition flow management. I played full-stack role in this project.

### **Dhaka Bank Loan Approval System**

Despite being a backend developer(django) I contributed in both backend and frontend (ReactJs) for this project . This project was about the central loan management system for the mentioned bank

#### **3P Exam Simulator**

I played my role as a front-end ReactJs developer for this project from scratch . This project scope was about complex exam logic with some fancy features

### **NIPN Data Repository**

I played my role as a front-end ReactJs developer for this project from scratch. This project intends to facilitate the set-up of a functional and effective information and analysis platform for nutrition within national structures that effectively analyses data to inform nutrition policies

### Some of my Personal Projects

#### Sports betting Site

Created full-featured sports betting sites using Python, Django, MYSQL, HTML, CSS, JS, Bootstrap.

### **Amarmess**

Created a full-featured mess management system Python Django, MYSQL, HTML, CSS, JS, Bootstrap

#### **Online Admission System**

Apply different educational institutes in online. Technology used Python, Django, MYSQL, Javascript, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS. Demo ☑

### **Finders Room Booking**

Rent or Book rooms online with Finder. Technology used Python, Django, MYSQL, Javascript, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS.

Demo 🛮

### **Trade Management**

Inventory management between different branches, track sell & purchase report and different roles management using Python Django, MYSQL, HTML, CSS, JS, Bootstrap.

Demo 🛮

### **Online Admission & Exam Site**

Created Online Admission and Exam System for an Islamic institution MarkazunNahda using Python, Django, Postgres, Javascript, HTML, CSS

Demo ☑

L	a	n	g	u	a	g	es	;

English  $\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet$  Bangla  $\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet$ 

## Workshop

I have completed a 2 session total 16 class workshop on Data Science using Python, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib under the Edward M. Kennedy Center.